For the road images you've seen, you know that they're all composed of red,
これまでに見た道路の画像は
green, and blue values or RGB.
すべて赤 緑 青の値 つまりRGBで構成されていることがわかります
And in the past, you've used some combination of masking and
これまでは これらのRGB値にマスキングと色のしきい値の組み合わせを使って
color thresholds on these RGB values to pick out bright white lane pixels.
明るい白の車線のピクセルを選択してきました
And this lane detection can work well alongside gradient detection
この車線検出は
which relies on grayscale intensity measurements.
グレースケール強度測定に依存する勾配検出と一緒に機能することができます
However, RGB thresholding doesn't work that well in images that include varying
ただし さまざまな照明条件を含む画像や車線が黄色のような異なる色である場合は
light conditions or when lanes are a different color like yellow.
RGBしきい値処理はそれほどうまくいきません
Let me show you what I mean.
私が意図していることをお見せしましょう
Take this image of a road.
この道路の画像を見てください
We can break it down into it's separate RGB components
チャネルと呼ばれる
which are often called channels.
別々のRGBコンポーネントに分解することができます
Here are the three channels represented in grayscale intensity.
これがグレースケール強度で表された3つのチャネルです
The brighter pixels indicate higher values of red, green, or blue,
より明るいピクセルが
respectively.
それぞれ赤 緑 または青の高い値を示します
Looking at the lane lines, you can see that the red and
車線を見ると 赤と緑のチャネルが
green channels are high for both the white and yellow lane lines.
白と黄色の車線の両方で高いことがわかります
But if we look at the blue channel,
しかし 青のチャネルを見ると
there's almost no blue component in the yellow lane.
黄色の車線には青の成分はほとんどありません
So the R and G channels will be the most useful for isolating both white and
そのため RとGチャネルは
yellow lane pixels.
白と黄色の両方の車線ピクセルを分離するのに最も役立ちます
But you can also see that the red and green values change
しかし 赤と緑の値は
under different levels of brightness at the back of the image.
画像の背景の明るさのレベルが異なると変化することもわかります
They get lower under shadow and
これらの色は影の下では低くなり
don't consistently recognize the lane under extreme brightness.
極端な明るさの下では一貫して車線を認識しません
Let's see if there's a better way to detect these lanes.
これらの車線を検出するためのより良い方法がないか見ていきましょう
There are many other ways to represent the colors in an image
赤 緑 青の値だけで構成する以外にも
besides just composed of red, green and blue values.
画像内の色を表現する方法はたくさんあります
These different color representations are often called color spaces.
これらの異なる色表現は多くの場合 色空間と呼ばれます
RGB is red, green, blue color space.
RGBは赤 緑 青から成る色空間です
You can think of this as a 3D space where
これは3D空間であり この場合は立方体と考えることができます
any color can be represented by a 3D coordinate of R, G, and B values.
ここでは任意の色をR G およびBの値の3D 標で表すことができます
There's also HSV color space, for hue, saturation, and value.
HSV色空間(色相 彩度 値)
And there's HLS, for hue, lightness, and saturation.
およびHLS空間(色相 明度 彩度)もあります
These are some of the most commonly used color spaces in image analysis.
これらは 画像解析で最も一般的に使用されている色空間です
For both of these, H has a range from 0 to 179 for
どちらの場合も 円柱色空間の周囲の度数について
degrees around the cylindrical color space.
Hの範囲は0～179です
And you can see details about the mathematical conversion from RGB to HLS
また RGBからHLS空間への数学的変換についての詳細は
space in the notes below.
下記の注にあります
We'll be going through an example in HLS color space.
HLS色空間の例を見ていきましょう
This isolates the lightness or L component of each pixel in an image.
これは 画像内の各ピクセルの明度またはL成分を分離します
And this is the component that varies the most under different lighting
そしてこれは さまざまな照明条件下で
conditions.
最も変化する要素です
But the H and S channels stay fairly consistent under shadow or
しかし HチャネルとSチャネルは シャドウや過度の明るさの下でも
excessive brightness.
ほぼ一貫しています
And if we use these channels only and
また これらのチャネルのみを使って
discard the information in the L channel, we should be able to detect
Lチャンネルの情報を破棄すると
different colors of lane lines more reliably than in RGB color space.
RGB色空間よりも確実に 異なる色の車線の色を検出できます
Here's that same RGB road image converted to HLS color space.
これは 同じRGB道路画像をHLS色空間に変換したものです
If we break it down into the separate H, L, and S channels,
これを別々のH L Sチャネルに分解すると
we can really see the difference between this color space and RGB color space.
この色空間とRGB色空間の違いがわかります
Here, it looks like the S channel detects lane lines pretty well,
ここでは Sチャネルが車線をはっきりと検出し
as well as dark sections of the H channel.
Hチャンネルの暗い部分も検出しているように見えます
And we can use this channels to create a smart color threshold
このチャネルを使って
that reliably detects lane line pixels of different colors.
異なる色の車線ピクセルを確実に検出するスマートカラーしきい値を作成できます
Let see an example of color thresholding in code next.
次にコード内のカラーしきい値の例を見てみましょう